<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Paul Warren</title>
		<description>An Internaught</description>
		<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://blog.pwarren.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>SOTA Activation of Black Mountain</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Got out to another SOTA summit today, VK1/AC-042. Started off on 2m and got VK1MA, booming in strong as always, not much further luck on 2m, so attempted to get going on HF, but there were problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;right larger&#39;&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2014-09-21-sota_01.jpg&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2014-09-21-sota_01.jpg&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Telecom (not Telstra, damnit!) Tower&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called for a little while, and heard nothing come back, sent a spot to sotawatch, and then heard quite a few come in, but I had very poor signal reports, and VK1MA suggested something was very wrong as I was only signal strength 1, line of sight to his QTH, I should be some dB over strength 9! Tweaking things around a bit, I found that the patch lead I repaired last week, is still no good :( If I look at it in the right tone of voice, and hold it just right, it works, but it’s flakey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some debugging on 2m, and moving the FT-817 off the metal rail to improve 2m SWR and signal reports, I got 2 more contacts and a summit to summit with VK1NAM on Mt Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;right larger&#39;&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2014-09-21-sota_02.jpg&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2014-09-21-sota_02.jpg&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;SOTA station nearly packed up&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that I tried the end fed wire straight into the LDG 817H tuner, without the 4:1 transformer, which worked fine! Tuned up 1:1 without issue on 40 and 20m. I proceeded to catch 15 more contacts, including 2 summit to summit on 40m with a much improved signal report of 58 to 59 for the most part! I also managed my first contact to England, with a summit to summit on 20m to 2E0YYY which was very cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did remember photos this time, but only after I’d started packing up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of the easy summits in Canberra, next one I’ll have to walk a bit further! I’m not sure that I’ll have time to activate next weekend, but I’ll try out the other bands in the back yard with just the tuner, and see how I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Monday I’m in Tassie, hoping that the associatin is live so I can activate down there, fingers crossed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(And yay, I finally figured out a bit more about the fancybox plugin for jekyll!)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/21/Black-Mt.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/21/Black-Mt.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>SOTA Activation of Mt Stromlo</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I got my second SOTA activation done yesterday on Mt Stromlo, VK1/AC-043. I wanted to test out my gear, and make sure everything works, before I head to Tasmania in a few weeks, hopefully arriving after the SOTA association for VK7 goes live!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the Ok by my wife, I drove to the hill! I parked at the rocks and locked gate past the ruins of the telescope, where quite a few mountain bikers were also parked, walked up and scouted around a bit at the trig and the communications gear on the top, before descending the necessary 25m and coming back up again. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first tried my newly built 2m Yagi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2m_yagi.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2m_yagi.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and managed to contact VK1EM and VK1MA, proving that the antenna ‘works’, I’ll give it a bit more of a workout on the next VHF field day I hope!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After calling for another 15 minutes with no luck, I set up for HF with the also new squidpole from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.haverford.com.au&quot;&gt;Haverfords&lt;/a&gt;, they’d run out of the heavy duty ones, so I have a 9m medium duty pole, it seems to do the trick! My HF antenna is an end fed wire 22m long, with a 4:1 balun and counterpoise, and has worked in the back yard very well over the last month or so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had it just about ready to go, and the squidpole fell over. Note for next time, take two, or perhaps three ties to attach the pole to a handy tree!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with a handy rock bracing the pole, I attempted to get started! And found that my tuner wasn’t getting a tune on 40m! The patch cables I’ve made are a little unreliable, mostly because I had no idea how to actually stick the damn things to the coax! I’ve rectified that now, so next time there shouldn’t be any cabling issues!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I tried to find a free spot on the band, which was non-trivial, twice in a row the frequency I was listening to had someone come up, just as I’d posted the spot on SotaWatch. Perhaps I need to listen for a bit longer before spotting? Any way, plowed through a good number of VK3s and vk2s and another VK1 on 40m, easily getting my 4 QSOs for the summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then had a crack at 20m! I thought 40m was busy, I could hardly find a spot on 20m, and eventually had one single contact, with DL1DVE, my first German contact. That was all I could get on 20m, the band was very busy with Europeans, I called for another 20 minutes or so and heard nothing, I think I probably needed a bit more punch to get through!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By that time I was getting a bit cool, a stiff westerly had come up and the sun had just about gone! All up 11 QSOs, in 1h45m on the hill. Thanks to all the chasers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sillily, I didn’t take any photos this time! Too busy thinking about radios! Next time I’ll try and remember!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/14/Mt-Stromlo.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/14/Mt-Stromlo.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Ocf Dipole Up!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed to string up an 80m Off Centre Fed Dipole over the weekend, I managed a contact to Kentucky, USA, on 20m, and got a 59 report with my 100W and his gigantic yagi of doom! Also had a half dozen SOTA contacts on 40m and 20m over Sunday afternoon, so it’s fair to say it works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had taken some photos, but it’s actually really hard to see it in them! It’s just some wires running through the trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I spent some time with the local club’s MFJ analyser (Thanks Gilbert!) and got an SWR graph of the antenna as installed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/ocf_swr.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/ocf_swr.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheet available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1HkWkwKKXdAVkZsj5o_kiEOkqZ5DnnjBpoTTgiWST81U/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;google drive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salient points: Lowest frequency minimum SWR: 1.9 @ 3.455MHz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other minimums:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.8 @ 7.133 MHz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1.2 @ 14.494 MHz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1.4 @ 18.046 MHz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1.3 @ 25.252 MHz&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1.5 @ 29.006 MHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that telling me I should shorten it a touch, to get the lowest frequency dip up into the 80m band a bit more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m running my Kenwood TS-140S to it through an MFJ 986 manual tuner, which is able to get it to 1:1 SWR on 80, 40 20, 17, 12 and 10m without much difficulty, so I may just leave it as is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Haven’t tried 15 and 30m yet, is that going to be possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d also managed to put a station ground in a few weekends ago, which has reduced the RFI to my PC’s audio system, but, my house alarm still goes off if I try any mode other than SSB voice. FM, AM and JT65 modes, will set it off at varying power levels, FM and AM only at full output power, nominally 50W, and JT65, even at 10W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m told there are a few options to attempt remedying this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put common mode chokes on the wires of the alarm system that go to the various devices around the house, 10 turns around one or two t130-2s&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Put capacitors between the signal wire and the alarm board&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;replace cables with screened ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having further thoughts, it may be 433MHz reciever for the key fobs being overloaded, as you can set off the lights and sirens by pressing all the buttons on the fob, and from the keypad, but it’s a special mode, not set off by sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May have to ring the installer, see if he’s got any tips!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/09/OCF-Dipole-Up%21.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/09/09/OCF-Dipole-Up%21.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>5w Dx!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Woooo! Pretty excited, i had a day off yesterday, and in the afternoon thought I’d have a bit of a play with radios, and finally got a good DX SSB contact with my 5W OzQRP MST2. I managed to get to Europe, Coray France to be a bit more precise. It was with Frank, F5PAU, he’s running 1KW into a yagi, a pretty impressive setup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could read Frank a good 5 x 10 over 9 with my dipole, and I received a 5 x 1, tho had to repeat my callsign a bit for it to be copyable! But once that was done, Frank did not seem to have trouble understanding me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it’s true 5W can get you to the world :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/28/5W-DX%21.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/28/5W-DX%21.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Rd Contest And New Radio</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of fun on Saturday with the wia’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wia.org.au/members/contests/rdcontest/&quot;&gt;Rememberance Day&lt;/a&gt; amateur radio contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have recently acquired an ft817 radio, along with an LDG z817H auto-tuner, which makes like a whole lot easier! I didn’t realise how much of a limit being stuck on 20m was. This late in the solar cycle 20m is not as impressive as it can be, but 40m was where it was at, of 22 contacts I made as a QRP station, 2 were on 20m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to get the antenna tuner to cope with my 40m end fed half wave antenna, I had to build a 4:1 transformer balun, which was relatively easy in the end, and seemed to work very well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2014-08-17-RD-Setup.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2014-08-17-RD-Setup.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve since boxed up the BALUN, and it looks quite nice, an is potentially useful as a balun for a QRP OCF too, tho the tuner can cope with end fed on pretty much all bands 40m and up, tho I’ve only confirmed that it works on 40 and 20, with no other stations to contact on other bands that I could hear!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2014-08-17-BALUN.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2014-08-17-BALUN.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought the gear to be my main SOTA portable station, so setting up the contest station in the back yard was a good poving ground for it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next items to sort out are a decent battery pack and a squidpole, then I’ll be fully ready for extended SOTA activations. Then I’ll just need to improve my fitness so I can walk up the hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll put it out there: My goal is to activate Booroomba Rocks by the end of the year. This involves an hour bushwalk, the first 30 minutes on a walking track, then overland to the summit, carrying all the aforementioned gear, staying for some hours, and then walking back again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be doing some other activations that are a bit easier to get to, some with carparks at the top before then, to practice my radio operation, and de-bug equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be heading to Tassie in October, hope the association is up and running when I get there :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/17/RD-Contest-and-new-radio.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/17/RD-Contest-and-new-radio.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>70cm Yagi</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I know a bit more about antennas and why using a dipole in a yagi isn’t so good, I decided to build a new one, following the WA5VJB’s designs found on his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wa5vjb.com/yagi-pdf/cheapyagi.pdf&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took me about an hour to stick it together&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/2014-08-11-70cm_yagi.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/2014-08-11-70cm_yagi.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortuantely, the SWR is a minimum at 2 bars of SWR on an FT817, at 443.5MHz, a bit off the design frequency of 432.2MHz where the FT-817 shows 8 bars :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have to have another crack at the folded dipole. I think I know what the problem is, I started folding the wire round a 1/2 inch former at the wrong spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/11/70cm-Yagi.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/11/70cm-Yagi.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>New Callsign</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;After passing my Advanced exam a few weeks ago, I’m now known as VK1ATP! Hope to hear you over the air!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/04/New-Callsign.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/08/04/New-Callsign.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Sota Activation</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Today was the VK1 (And most of the rest of VK!) &lt;a href=&quot;http://sota.org.uk&quot;&gt;SOTA&lt;/a&gt; party, and I did my first ever activation on Mt Ainslie, VK1/AC-040, and had a bit of fun! I learnt just how far down the hill the activation zone starts, 25m altitude is a bit further than I thought!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my chair at the summit pole, the end fed antenna is strung up in the trees to the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/SOTA-2014-07-27.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/SOTA-2014-07-27.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get my Beach40 working in time, so I was on 20m, 2m and 70cm. Managed 9 contacts, 7 of which were Summit 2 Summit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Frequency&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Mode&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Call&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Summit&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:01&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;439.000MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1RW/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-035&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Rob!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;439.000MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK2FAJW/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-038&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Andrew!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;14.320MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1RX/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Al!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:15&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;146.5MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1DI/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-023&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Ian!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;146.5MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1DSH&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Dale!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:17&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;146.5MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1NAM/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-032&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks Andrew!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;14.310MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1MA/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-042&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:35&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;14.310MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK8MA/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S57R52 Thanks Greg!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;00:47&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;14.305MHz&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;SSB&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1EM/P&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;VK1/AC-043&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;S59R59 Thanks!&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;40m was where it was at, with some of the other guys getting over 60 contacts! So, for next time, I’d better get the beach40 fixed, or figure out a different way to get the band up!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/27/Sota-Activation.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/27/Sota-Activation.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Boxed And Ready To Go</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Well, the Beach40 is boxed up and ready to test! Just working out what else I need to check before putting it on the air! Hopefully I’ll be set up at 04:00 UTC tomorrow (2014-07-08), listen out somewhere between 7.007 and 7.230 :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-01.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-01.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-02.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-02.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-03.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/Beach40-2014-07-18-03.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/18/Boxed-and-Ready-to-Go.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/18/Boxed-and-Ready-to-Go.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Weekend&#39;s Efforts</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Had a bit of a quiet weekend, didn’t get a huge amount of radio stuff done, instead mostly housework, looking after the kids and on call work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I got my dummy load built:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/qrp_dummyload.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/qrp_dummyload.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s 1.0 SWR from 1.5MHz until about 6MHz, then 1.1 until 12MHz, then 1.3 until 18Mhz, 1.5 at 27MHz, and then stays there until about 70Mhz where it jumps to 2.0. Theres a dip down to 1.2 at ~110MHz, then back up to 2.0 by 120MHz and stays there until 155Mhz, which s the limit of the analyser I’m borrowing. Yes, I’ll shorten that lead to the signal side of the board!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it should be good for testing my beach40, and other bits that I build! I used 44 * 2k2 Ohm 1/2 watt resistors. It measures 51.3 Ohms across them with my cheapo jaycar multimeter, and should be able to dissapate 10 watts easily, dont’ think I’ll try putting 20W through it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I have the detector right yet, there are various designs around the web, and I’ll have to keep tinkering to see what works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also made a start on the enclosure for my Beach40, it’s an old PC power supply box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class=&#39;fancybox&#39; href=&#39;/images/beach40_enclosure.png&#39; rel=&#39;group&#39;&gt;&lt;img src=&#39;/images/beach40_enclosure.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve trimmed the board I built the beach40 on to fit, and it’s nice and snug, will have to figure out mounting. I think double sided tape will be the go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled out the PSU PCB and discovered why it didn’t work, one of the resistors had carbonised! But there are some nice components on it for the junque box, some nice big toroids and capacitors, a bunch of 12v regulators with heatsinks and a couple of transformers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s some slots in one side where the modular power cables came out, which are a pretty good fit for the antenna ports. I’ll be spending this week fitting on the connectors and working out how to mount the PCB. Then final TX adjustment on the dummy load, and hook up to it’s end-fed antenna to see if reception is Ok.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/14/Weekend%27s-Efforts.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//radio/2014/07/14/Weekend%27s-Efforts.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
