<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Paul Warren</title>
		<description>A geek of various shades</description>
		<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://blog.pwarren.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Roasting Setup</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I use an Ozito heatgun with a digital temperature gague, and a beat up Sunbeam Bakehouse breadmaker. I made a fibre-cement top with a hole for the heat gun to sit in, and one for chaff to exit! I’ve had this setup since December 2011, and it’s been awesome, fresh roasted coffee all the time is a big plus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also got a bathroom exhaust fan stuck in a bucket with salastic, below a drum sieve to cool the beans post roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve yet to sort out the breadmaker properly, it still turns off if I try to do a second roast straight away. Need to work out how to pull it apart and short or remove the temperature sensor!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/roasting02_post.jpg' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/roasting02_post.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Coretto roasting setup with pre drum sieve cooler&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//coffee/2014/02/04/roasting-setup.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//coffee/2014/02/04/roasting-setup.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Attempt No.1 to receive Ardusat</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I built an antenna as specified here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://forums.snapstream.com/vb/showthread.php?t=38708&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here’s what my version looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/433MHz_yagi_post.jpg' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/433MHz_yagi_post.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;433 MHz Yagi Antenna&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attempted to receive ArduSat-X and ArduSat-1, and I think I saw the CW beacon of ArduSat-X with &lt;a href=&quot;http://gqrx.de&quot;&gt;gqrx&lt;/a&gt; but I hadn’t adjusted for the doppler effect, or something, because it appeared some distance away from 437.000MHz. And I only recorded the last few symbols, not even a full letter of morse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next little while, I’ll try to construct a flow graph in GnuRadio that’ll let me see the FFT waterfall, hear where I’m tuned to, and record the raw IQ values for the whole range, so I can come back later and decode the FM CW beacon at the corrected location!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2014/02/02/Ardusat-contact-attempt1.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2014/02/02/Ardusat-contact-attempt1.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>RTL-entropy Lightning Talk</title>
				<description>&lt;div class='video-container'&gt;&lt;iframe height='420' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/RWn5QJpOBFU?html5=1' width='560'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RWn5QJpOBFU'&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick talk I did about my rtl-entropy software: https://github.com/pwarren/rtl-entropy/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//talks/2014/01/27/rtl-entropy.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//talks/2014/01/27/rtl-entropy.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>EFI single boot on a MacBook Air</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;EFI needs its own smallish partition with a fat32 filesystem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here’s my layout with just one disk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   (parted) print
   Model: ATA Hitachi HTS54503 (scsi)
   Disk /dev/sda: 320GB
   Sector size (logical/physical): 512B/512B
   Partition Table: gpt
   
   Number Start End Size File system Name Flags
   1 1049kB 512MB 511MB fat32 boot
   2 512MB 316GB 316GB ext4
   3 316GB 320GB 4023MB linux-swap(v1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, debian does sort of support UEFI booting with the 7.2 install discs (haven’t tried 7.3 yet but should be good), but there was some extra mucking about I had to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve installed, and it boots the flashing folder icon (or question mark, I forget which). Boot into rescue mode, and let debian find the right root partition, and execute a shell in that partition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mount /boot/efi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install grub-efi-amd64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re almost there! the installer for grub-efi-amd64 puts the boot file in /efi/EFI/debian/grub64x64.efi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we need to put that in the right place for EFI to load it properly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir /boot/efi/EFI/boot
cp /boot/efi/EFI/debian/grubx64.efi /boot/efi/EFI/boot/bootx64.efi&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;update-grub&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure all the configs are in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then reboot! and you should eventually get into debian :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a white screen for ~30s after the boot chime, and you want to get rid of the wait, you’ll have to boot an OS X disk and run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bless --device /dev/disk0s1 --setBoot --verbose&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;substituting the proper device node for your boot device of course.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2013/12/17/EFI-single-boot-mac.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2013/12/17/EFI-single-boot-mac.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Firefox i386 on Debian amd64</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Goto http://getfirefox.com/ and download the latest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; tar -jxvf firefox-*.tar.bz2
 sudo mv firefox /opt
 sudo dpkg --add-architecture i386
 sudo apt-get update

 sudo apt-get install libc6:i386 libstdc++6:i386 libxrender1:i386 libasound2:i386 libdbus-glib-1-2:i386 libxext6:i386 libgtk2.0-0:i386 libxt6:i386 libcurl3:i386 libnss3:i386 libnspr4:i386 libssl1.0.0:i386&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  /opt/firefox/firefox
  should work.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next get the 32 bit tar.gz file for adobe flash, unpack and copy it to /opt/firefox/browser/plugins/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; tar -zxvf install_flash_player_11_linux.i386.tar.gz
 mkdir -p /opt/firefox/browser/plugins

 cp libflashplayer.so /opt/firefox/browser/plugins&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you should be good to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2013/10/21/firefox-i386-on-debian-amd64.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//tech/2013/10/21/firefox-i386-on-debian-amd64.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Stories from Ellen</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Mum very much wanted me to go into kindergartern. So on Mondays on the back of dad’s motorbike down to the river, the ferry didn’t leave until 8, but dad needed to get to his shift by 7:45, so on a rowing boat across the river to the canteen lady at the zinc works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to Auntie Dolcie and Nelly who had no idea about kids. Of course, on fridays the process was all in reverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A boarder at Auntie Dolcies remarked that he’d never seen such an unhappy 5 year od, so that put paid to Kindergarten. Mostly because I had no one to play with and no houses anywhere near with children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I had to walk a mile every day to school from age 6. Jim and others included when they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Peter was less than 2, he pulled out a toilet roll and put it in the toilet and kpet flushing until it went away! THere was water halfway to the front door, he didn’t really know what was happening, didn’t know it was him doing it all! emptied the storage Tank.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//family/2013/05/21/Stories-from-Ellen.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//family/2013/05/21/Stories-from-Ellen.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Random Notes</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Emma Coffee, Born London, migrated to Aus 1920-1922, worked at the Woolwich arsenal during the First War, then worked in the paper shop, her father (James, not certain), was a baker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eileen (Fred’s Sister) told Ellen that when Emma and Arthur were leaving to come to Australia, Emma’s father went to see them off and having never met him before, said “He’ll never support you lass!”, he never did. Knocked her about terribly when drunk, which was often. Died when Fred was 16. that’s why Fred’s brother joined the AIF, not Fred, to support her. Fred came in a later induction where they didn’t look so closely at medical problems, fred had an intermittently discharging ear from his bad pneumonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred’s family: Rhona (has a lake named after her in the south west of Tasmania) Eileen, Effie, Fred, Beatrice Louise, Margurita Elizabeth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irish Pharmaceutical diplomas not recognised in Australia so Arthur was a sort of Vet, clients would pay him in grog and send him home blotto, instead of giving him some potatoes to feed the children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In amongst 4 births and many miscarriages Emma was the farm’s housekeeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rhona became an accountant, Eileen and Effie Nurses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred Had blackouts, once he remembered coming back into the camp gates in the Captains car, who had found him a few miles away wandering about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cousins were watching a movie in a ditch, where’s Fred? Unconscious in the ditch. Insulin shock therapy, made it a lot worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fred had told me (Paul) that it was shell shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His sisters think it was some sort of abscess in his head from chronic pneumonia he suffered as a child, which does seem more likely!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point during the 70s or 80s, the laws changed, so that if you went into the army without a condition, and came out with a condition, it was classed as “War Caused”. Making fred a TPI War Veteran, and Ellen a War Widow when he passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This made life a lot easier for the Blaydon St Warrens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//family/2013/05/21/Random-Notes.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//family/2013/05/21/Random-Notes.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Plum Sauce</title>
				<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 lbs egg plums&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;3 pints vinegar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tblsp salt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tblsp cloves&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 lb onions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;3 lbs sugar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cayenne&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tblsp spice&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tblsp whole ginger (bruised)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boil all ingredients together for one hour, then strain through a colander, and bottle when cold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//recipes/2013/05/20/plum-sauce.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//recipes/2013/05/20/plum-sauce.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Tomato Sauce</title>
				<description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 lbs Tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;6 pints vinegar&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 tsp Cayenne&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 oz cloves&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;2 oz spice&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1 1/4 lbs salt&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;6 lbs green apples&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;4 lbs onions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;2 ozs white pepper&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;2 ozs whole ginger&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;4 ozs garlic&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;5 lbs white suger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut up apples, Tomatoes and onions and put int preserving pan with all other ingredients and boil for 2.5 to 3 hours stirring frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strain through a fine colander, bottle, cork, seal and label.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://blog.pwarren.id.au//recipes/2013/05/19/tomato-sauce.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.pwarren.id.au//recipes/2013/05/19/tomato-sauce.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
